Guide to the Marilyn Horne Foundation Records, 1991-2011 CTC.2010.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Audio/Visual Materials, 1995-2010; IV.
  - On Wings of Song, 1995-2010; 2.
    - 2007-2008 Season
      - Recital, November 11, 2007 (Box 144, Folder 1)
        - Live recording, CD, 60 minutes
        - WQXR radio broadcast, November 24, 2007; CD, 59 minutes
        - Video recording, 2 Mini DV tapes, 60 minutes
      - Recital, February 8, 2008 (Box 144, Folder 2)
        On Wings of Song recital at The Saint Louis Art Museum, St. Louis.
        Presented by the Marilyn Horne Foundation and The Saint Louis Art Museum.
        Dimitri Pittas, tenor; Carrie-Ann Matheson, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 70 minutes
      - Recital, April 13, 2008 (Box 144, Folder 3)
        On Wings of Song recital at Christ & St. Stephen's Church, NYC.
        - Live recording, CD, 60 minutes
        - WQXR radio broadcast, April 26, 2008; CD, 60 minutes
        - Video recording, 2 Mini DV tapes, 60 minutes
      - Recital, May 4, 2008 (Box 144, Folder 4)
        Nicholas Phan, tenor; Jeremy Frank, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 63 minutes
        - WQXR radio broadcast, May 17, 2008; CD, 59 minutes
        - Video recording, Mini DV, 60 minutes
    - 2008-2009 Season
      - Recital, October 5, 2008 (Box 144, Folder 5)
        Featuring the 2008 MHF Awardees at the Music Academy of the West.
        Edward Parks, baritone; In Sun Suh, piano.
        - Live recording, 2 CDs, 95 minutes
        - WQXR radio broadcast, October 18, 2008; CD, 63 minutes
        - Video recording, DVD, 91 minutes
        - Video recording, 2 Mini DV tapes, 90 minutes
      - Recital, November 2, 2008 (Box 144, Folder 6)
        Jonathan Beyer, baritone; Mikael Eliasen, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 70 minutes
        - WQXR radio broadcast, November 15, 2008; CD, 60 minutes
        - Video recording, 2 Mini DV tapes, 70 minutes
      - Recital, March 8, 2009 (Box 144, Folder 7)
        Jennifer Zetlan, soprano; David Shimoni, piano; Ken Noda, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 67 minutes
        - WQXR radio broadcast, March 21, 2009; CD, 62 minutes
        - Video recording, DVD, 62 minutes
        - Video recording, Mini DV, 60 minutes
      - Recital, April 19, 2009 (Box 144, Folder 8)
        Joslin Romphf, soprano; Caren Levine, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 60 minutes
        - WQXR radio broadcast, May 2, 2009; CD, 60 minutes
        - Video recording, Mini DV, 60 minutes
    - 2009-2010 Season
      - Recital, October 18, 2009 (Box 144, Folder 9)
        Paul Appleby, tenor; Steven Blier, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 70 minutes
        - Video recording, 2 Mini DV tapes, 70 minutes
      - Recital, November 22, 2009 (Box 144, Folder 10)
        Presented by the Marilyn Horne Foundation and the Weill Music Institute at Carnegie Hall.
        Simone Osborne, soprano; Carrie-Ann Matheson, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 67 minutes
        - Video recording, 2 Mini DV tapes, 70 minutes
      - Recital, February 14, 2010 (Box 144, Folder 11)
        Featuring the 2009 MHF Award Winners at the Music Academy of the West
        Jeffrey Hill, tenor; Ronnita Miller, mezzo soprano; Lio Kuokman, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 70 minutes
      - Recital, March 21, 2010 (Box 144, Folder 12)
        Tamara Mumford, mezzo soprano; Ken Noda, piano; Eric Nowlin, viola.
        - Live recording, CD, 70 minutes
        - Video recording, Mini DV, 40 minutes
      - Recital, April 8, 2010 (Box 144, Folder 13)
        On Wings of Song recital at Hahn Hall, Music Academy of the West, Santa Barbara.
        Alek Shrader, tenor; Keun-A Lee, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 70 minutes
        - KDB93.7 radio broadcast, Date unknown; CD, 63 minutes
      - Recital, April 11, 2010 (Box 144, Folder 14)
        On Wings of Song recital at Santa Monica College for the Performing Arts (Broad Stage), Santa Monica.
        Presented by the Marilyn Horne Foundation and the Eli and Edythe Broad Stage.
        - Live recording, CD, 77 minutes
  - The Song Continues, 1996-2010; 3.
    The Song Continues... Festival is the Marilyn Horne Foundation's annual festival that focuses on the art song. The annual festival included the gala concert, several masterclass by world-renown singers, vocal seminars, and other duo recitals by the Foundation's roster of artists. These recordings are arranged in chronological order. Each performance contains a note with venue and artist information, the format of the recording, and the length.
    - 1996 Festival
      - Annual recital, January 16, 1996 (Box 145, Folder 1)
        Song Continues annual recital at Alice Tully Hall at Lincoln Center, NYC.
        Michelle DeYoung, mezzo soprano; Bruce Ford, tenor; Rodney Gilfry, baritone; Janet Williams, soprano; Jerry Hadley, tenor (Surprise Guest); Thomas Bagwell, piano; Warren Jones, piano; and Brian Zeger, piano.
        - Live recording, 2 audio DVDs, 139 minutes
        - Live recording, 2 digital audio cassettes, 139 minutes
        - WQXR radio broadcast, January 27, 1996; 2 CDs, 113 minutes
        - Video recording, 2 dvds, 127 minutes
        - Video recording, 2 Betacam SP cassettes, 127 minutes
    - 1998 Festival
      - Seminar, January 15, 1998 (Box 146, Folder 1-4)
        Song Continues seminar at the Juilliard Theater at Lincoln Center, NYC.
        Dame Joan Sutherland and Marilyn Horne discuss vocal technique
        - Video recording - Camera angle 1, 4 Betacam SP cassettes, 90 minutes
        - Video recording - Camera angle 1, 4 dvds, 90 minutes
        - Video recording - Camera angle 2, 4 Betacam SP cassettes, 90 minutes
        - Video recording - Camera angle 2, 4 dvds, 90 minutes
      - Master Class, January 15, 1998 (Box 147, Folder 1-4)
        Song Continues masterclass at the Juilliard Theater at Lincoln Center, NYC.
        Dame Joan Sutherland
        - Video recording - Camera angle 1, 5 Betacam SP cassettes, 120 minutes
        - Video recording - Camera angle 1, 5 DVDs, 120 minutes
        - Video recording - Camera angle 2, 5 DVDs, 120 minutes
        - Video recording - Camera angle 2, 5 Betacam SP cassettes, 120 minutes
      - Annual recital, January 16, 1998 (Box 148, Folder 1)
        Song Continues annual recital at Carnegie Hall, NYC.
        David Daniels, countertenor; Frank Lopardo, tenor; Samuel Ramey, bass baritone; Rinat Shaham, mezzo soprano; Lynnette Tapia, soprano; Benita Valente, soprano; Deborah Voigt, soprano; Guang Yang, mezzo soprano; Dolora Zajick, mezzo soprano; Thomas Bagwell, piano; Warren Jones, piano; Martin Katz, piano; Brian Zeger, piano; Dame Joan Sutherland, Honored Guest.
        - Live recording, CD, 79 minutes
        - WQXR radio broadcast, January 31, 1998; 2 CDs, 144 minutes
    - 1999 Festival
      - Annual recital, January 15, 1999 (Box 148, Folder 2)
        Song Continues annual recital at the Juilliard Theater at Lincoln Center, NYC.
        Stephanie Blythe, mezzo soprano; Brian Leerhuber, baritone; Nicole Heaston, soprano; Bejun Mehta, countertenor; Martin Katz, piano; Warren Jones, piano; Brian Zeger, piano.
        - WQXR radio broadcast, January 23, 1999; 3 CDs, 148 minutes
    - 2000 Festival
      - Annual recital, January 16, 2000 (Box 148, Folder 3)
        Song Continues annual recital at the Juilliard Theater at the Isaac Stern Auditorium, NYC
        Isabel Bayrakdarian, soprano; David Daniels, countertenor; Brian Farrell, piano; Renee Fleming, Soprano; Jerry Hadley, tenor; Warren Jones, piano; Martin Katz, piano; Lester Lynch, baritone; Carrie-Ann Matheson, piano; Bejun Mehta, countertenor; Bryn Terfel, baritone; Dolora Zajick, mezzo soprano; Brian Zeger, piano.
        - Live recording, 2 CDs, 130 minutes
    - 2001 Festival
      - Annual recital, January 19, 2001 (Box 148, Folder 4)
        Presented by the Marilyn Horne Foundation and the Juilliard School.
        Charles Castronovo, tenor; Jill Grove, mezzo soprano; Meagan Miller, soprano; Dae San No, baritone; Warren Jones, piano; Spencer Myer, piano; Brian Zeger, piano; Ruth Ann Swenson, Special guest artist (ill, replaced by Samuel Ramey)
        - WQXR radio broadcast, February 3, 2001; 2 CDs, 100 minutes
    - 2002 Festival
      - Annual recital, January 18, 2002 (Box 148, Folder 5)
        Lawrence Brownlee, tenor; Liesel Fedkenheuer, mezzo soprano; Monique McDonald, soprano; Keith Phares, baritone; Thomas Bagwell, piano; Miah Im, piano; Howard Watkins, piano; Brian Zeger, piano; Marvin Hamlisch, Special guest artist
        - Live recording, 2 CDs, 109 minutes
    - 2003 Festival
      - Annual recital, January 17, 2003 (Box 148, Folder 6)
        Keri Alkema, mezzo soprano; Jennifer Aylmer, soprano; Eric Cutler, tenor; James Westman, baritone; Martin Katz, piano; J.J. Penna, piano; Brian Zeger, piano; Grace Brumbry, Special guest artist
        - WQXR radio broadcast, January 25, 2003; 2 CDs, 86 minutes
    - 2004 Festival
      - Recital, January 28, 2004 (Box 148, Folder 7)
        Song Continues recital at the Weill Recital Hall at Carnegie Hall, NYC.
        Barbara Quintiliani, soprano; Bruce Sledge, tenor; Craig Terry, piano; Craig Ketter, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 72 minutes
      - Recital, January 30, 2004 (Box 148, Folder 8)
        Marie Lenormand, mezzo-soprano; Joshua Hopkins, baritone; Kenneth Merrill, piano; J.J. Penna, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 69 minutes
      - Annual recital, February 1, 2004 (Box 148, Folder 9-11)
        Song Continues annual recital at Isaac Stern Auditorium at Carnegie Hall, NYC.
        The Marilyn Horne Foundation presents the 10th anniversary gala concert and Marilyn Horne's 70th birthday celebration.
        Isabel Bayrakdarian, soprano; Stephanie Blythe, mezzo soprano; Olga Borodina, mezzo soprano; Barbara Cook, soprano; David Daniels, countertenor; Denyce Graves, mezzo soprano; Marvin Hamlish, piano; Ben Heppner, tenor Warren Jones, piano; Martin Katz, piano; Lang Lang, piano; Audra McDonald, soprano; Bejun Mehta, countertenor Tomas Quasthoff, bass baritone; Brian Stokes Mitchell, baritone; Twyla Robinson, soprano; Frederica von Stade, mezzo soprano.
        - Live recording, 2 CDs, 70 minutes
        - WQXR radio broadcast, February 14, 2004; CD, 62 minutes
        - Chevron Texaco Metropolitan Opera Radio Broadcast, January 24, 2004; CD, 5 minutes
          Birthday Tribute to Marilyn Horne including a brief biography and mentions MHF and the upcoming annual recital.
        - Video segments, 2003-2004; DVD, 117 minutes
          Segments played during annual recital celebrating Marilyn's 70th birthday. Included photo slideshows, birthday wishes, career highlights, etc.
        - Video segments - Birthday greetings, 2003-2004; 3 Betacam SP cassettes
        - Video segments - Birthday greetings, DVD, 3 minutes
    - 2005 Festival
      - Recital, January 26, 2005 (Box 149, Folder 1)
        Song Continues recital at the Weill Music Institute at Carnegie Hall, NYC.
        Presented by the Marilyn Horne Foundation and the Weill Music Institute at Carnegie Hall
        Deborah Domanski, mezzo soprano; Jason Hardy, bass; William Hobbs, piano; Jerome Tan, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 58 minutes
      - Recital, January 27, 2005 (Box 149, Folder 2)
        Jessica Jones, soprano; Weston Hurt, baritone; Brian Zegar, piano; Rachelle Jonck, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 55 minutes
      - Annual recital, January 28, 2005 (Box 149, Folder 3)
        Song Continues annual recital at Zankel Hall at Carnegie Hall, NYC.
        Erin Wall, soprano; Megan Latham, mezzo soprano; Simon O'Neill, tenor; Quinn Kelsey, baritone; Jonathan Kelly, piano; Carrie-Ann Matheson, piano; Spencer Myer, piano; Craig Rutenberg, piano; Brian Zeger, piano; René Pape, bass.
        - Live recording, 2 CDs, 121 minutes
        - WQXR broadcast version, February 12, 2005; 2 CDs, 108 minutes
        - Video recording, VHS, 123 minutes
    - 2006 Festival
      - Recital, January 25, 2006 (Box 149, Folder 4)
        Monica Yunus, soprano; Ian Greenlaw, baritone; Brian Zegar, piano; Howard Watkins, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 56 minutes
        - Video recording, VHS, 60 minutes
      - Recital, January 26, 2006 (Box 149, Folder 5)
        Daniela Lehner, mezzo-soprano; Erik Nelson Werner, baritone; Jerome Tan, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 65 minutes
        - Video recording, VHS, 68 minutes
      - Annual recital, January 27, 2006 (Box 149, Folder 6)
        Song Continues annual recital: Americans in Paris at Zankel Hall at Carnegie Hall, NYC.
        Nicole Cabell, soprano; Katherine Rohrer, mezzo soprano; William Ferguson, tenor; Nathaniel Webster, baritone; Frederica von Stade, special guest artist; Margo Garrett, piano; Martin Katz, piano; Kenneth Merrill, piano; Craig Rutenberg, piano.
        - Live recording, 2 CDs, 113 minutes
        - Live recording, 2 CDs, 120 minutes
        - WQXR broadcast version, February 11, 2006; 2 CDs, 101 minutes
        - WFMT radio broadcast, CD, 55 minutes
        - Video recording, VHS, 122 minutes
    - 2007 Festival
      - Recital, January 24, 2007 (Box 149, Folder 7)
        Joslin Romphf, soprano; Lee Poulis, baritone; Lydia Brown, piano; Thomas Muraco, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 49 minutes
      - Recital, January 25, 2007 (Box 149, Folder 8)
        Hanan Alattar, soprano; Timothy Fallon, tenor; Djordje Stevan Nesic, piano; Carol Wong, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 49 minutes
      - Annual recital, January 26, 2007 (Box 149, Folder 9)
        Song Continues annual recital: Gypsy in my Soul at Zankel Hall at Carnegie Hall, NYC.
        Erica Strauss, soprano; Sasha Cooke, mezzo soprano; Leonardo Capalbo, tenor; Andrew Garland, baritone; Vlad Iftinca, piano; Jonathan Kelly, piano; Donna Loewy, piano; Jerome Tan, piano; Warren Jones, piano; Marcello Giordani, special guest artist.
        - WQXR broadcast version, February 17, 2007; 2 CDs, 80 minutes
        - Sound Insights podcast - Interview with Barbara Cook and Marilyn Horne, December 19, 2006; CD, 18 minutes
        - Video recording, VHS, 100 minutes
    - 2008 Festival
      - Master Class, January 22, 2008 (Box 150, Folder 1)
        Song Continues master class at the Weill Recital Hall at Carnegie Hall, NYC.
        - Video recording, 2 DVDs, 121 minutes
      - Master Class, January 23, 2008 (Box 150, Folder 2)
        Graham Johnson
        - Video recording, 2 DVDs, 117 minutes
      - Recital, January 23, 2008 (Box 150, Folder 3)
        Amanda Majeski, soprano; Dimitri Pittas, tenor; Danielle Orlando, piano; Carrie-Ann Matheson, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 61 minutes
        - Video recording, DVD, 62 minutes
      - Master Class, January 24, 2008 (Box 150, Folder 4)
        Song Continues masterclass at Zankel Hall at Carnegie Hall, NYC.
        Dawn Upshaw
        - Video recording, 2 DVDs, 113 minutes
      - Recital, January 24, 2008 (Box 150, Folder 5)
        Brenda Rae, soprano; Eugene Chan, baritone; Keun-A Lee, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 60 minutes
        - Video recording, DVD, 61 minutes
        - Video recording, DVD, 46 minutes
      - Annual recital, January 25, 2008 (Box 150, Folder 6)
        Song Continues annual recital: Alumni celebration at Zankel Hall at Carnegie Hall, NYC.
        Stephanie Blythe, mezzo soprano; Rod Gilfry, baritone; Nicole Heaston, soprano; Evan Hughes, bass baritone; Meagan Miller, soprano; Garrett Sorenson, tenor; Guang Yang, mezzo soprano; Margo Garrett, piano; Brian Zeger, piano; Tamara Sanikidze, piano; Warren Jones, piano.
        - Live recording, 2 CDs, 88 minutes
        - Video recording, 2 DVDs, 124 minutes
    - 2009 Festival
      - Annual recital, January 18, 2009 (Box 150, Folder 7)
        Song Continues annual recital: 15th Anniversary Concert and Marilyn's 'Diamond' Birthday at the Isaac Stern Auditorium at Carnegie Hall, NYC.
        Meredit Arwady, contralto; William Bolcom, piano; Nicole Cabell, soprano; David Daniels, countertenor; Joyce Didonato, mezzo soprano; Susan Graham, mezzo soprano; Thomas Hampson, baritone; Dmitri Hvorostovsky, baritone; Warren Jones, piano; Martin Katz, piano; Isabel Leonard, mezzo soprano; Lester Lynch, baritone; Carrie-Ann Matheson, piano; Karita Mattila, soprano; James Morris, bass baritone; Thomas Quasthoff, bass baritone; Bruce Sledge, tenor; Dolora Zajick, mezzo soprano; Brian Zeger, piano; Hosted by Frederica von Stade and Samuel Ramey.
        Also are included are a series of birthday tributes from Marilyn Horne's friends and family; including Florence Henderson, Jim Nabors, Carol Burnett, Barbara Cook, Joan Sutherland, and Lotfi Mansouri.
        - WQXR broadcast version, January 31, 2009; 2 CDs, 110 minutes
        - Video recording, 3 DVDs, 164 minutes
        - Birthday wishes - Recording sessions, 2008; 7 dvds
        - Birthday wishes - Recording sessions, 2008; 7 Mini DV tapes
      - Master Class, January 20, 2009 (Box 150, Folder 8)
        Song Continues masterclass at the Weill Recital Hall at Carnegie Hall, NYC.
        Martin Katz
        - Video recording, DVD, 46 minutes
      - Recital, January 20, 2009 (Box 150, Folder 9)
        Jamie Barton, mezzo soprano; Russell Thomas, tenor; Kathleen Kelly, piano; Ken Noda, piano.
        - Video recording, DVD, 60 minutes
      - Recital, January 21, 2009 (Box 150, Folder 10)
        Susanna Phillips, soprano; Alex Shrader, tenor; Myra Huang, piano; Jerome Tan, piano.
        - Video recording, DVD, 70 minutes
      - Master Class, January 21, 2009 (Box 150, Folder 11)
        - Video recording, DVD, 109 minutes
      - Roundtable, January 22, 2009 (Box 150, Folder 12)
        Song Continues Marilyn and Friends roundtable discussion at the Weill Recital Hall at Carnegie Hall, NYC.
        Roundtable conversation with Marilyn Horne, Warren Jones, Benita Valente, and Barbara Hocher reflecting on the Foundation's first 15 years
        - Video recording, DVD, 62 minutes
      - Master Class, January 22, 2009 (Box 150, Folder 13)
        James Levine
        - Video recording, 2 DVDs, 124 minutes
      - Marilyn Horne tribute, February 2009 (Box 150, Folder 14-17)
        Marilyn Horne Foundation video shown during the 2009 annual recital. Birthday wishes are from friends and family including Joan Sutherland, Barbara Coook, Carol Burnett, Jim Nabors, etc.
        - Birthday wishes and photos from Marilyn Horne's career, DVD, 117 minutes
        - Birthday wishes - Raw recordings, 11 dvds
        - Birthday wishes - Raw recordings, 2008; 7 Mini DV tapes
        - Birthday wishes - Raw recordings, 2008-2009; Other formats, 6 tapes
    - 2010 Festival
      - Recital, January 19, 2010 (Box 150, Folder 18)
        Nadine Sierra, soprano; Edward Parks, baritone; Jerome Tan, piano; In Sun Suh, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 69 minutes
        - Video recording, DVD, 70 minutes
      - Recital, January 20, 2010 (Box 150, Folder 19)
        Sasha Cooke, soprano; Kelly Markgraf, baritone; Steven Blier, piano.
        - Live recording, CD, 71 minutes
        - Video recording, DVD, 71 minutes
      - Annual recital, January 22, 2010 (Box 150, Folder 20)
        Song Continues annual recital: Dames at "C" at Zankel Hall at Carnegie Hall, NYC.
        Keri Alkema, soprano; Elaine Alvarez, soprano; Amanda Majeski, soprano; Jennifer Zetlan, soprano; Kathleen Kim, soprano, Special guest; Michael Baitzer, piano; David Shimoni, piano; Tamara Sanikidze, piano; Warren Jones, piano.
        - Live recording, 2 CDs, 102 minutes
        - Video recording, 2 DVDs, 98 minutes
- Posters, 1998-2008; V.
  This series contains posters advertising the Horne Foundation's On Wings of Song and Song Continues programs along with posters relating to their national residency program recitals. The posters are arranged in alphabetical order by the location of the residency or the name of the show. Please note that some of the Song Continues posters in this series are oversized and are located at the Archives Service Center.
  - Ames Town & Gown Chamber Music Association, 2001-2005 (Box 151, Folder 1)
  - Art Song Festival, 2002 (Box 151, Folder 2)
  - Big Arts (Box 151, Folder 3)
  - Brownville Concert Series, 2001 (Box 151, Folder 4)
  - Center for the Performing Arts at Penn State, 2002-2003 (Box 151, Folder 5)
  - Huntsville Chamber Music Guild, 1998-2004 (Box 151, Folder 6)
  - Juilliard School, 2003 (Box 151, Folder 7)
  - Middlebury College Concert Series, 2000-2001 (Box 151, Folder 8)
  - Mozart Society of California, 2001-2003 (Box 151, Folder 9)
  - Office of the Mayor of the city of New York proclamation of Marilyn Horne Foundation Day - Signed by Rudolph W. Giuliani, January 16, 2000 (Box 151, Folder 10)
  - On Wings of Song, 2000-2004 (Box 151, Folder 11)
  - Riverside United Presbyterian Church, 2003 (Box 151, Folder 12)
  - Saint Mary's College, 2000 (Box 151, Folder 13)
  - Securing the Second Century: From Carnegie Hall to Marilyn Horne - Signed original artwork, March 9, 1998 (Box 151, Folder 14)
  - Song Continues, 1994-2008 (Box 151, Folder 15-25)
  - State University of New York Buffalo, 2003 (Box 151, Folder 26)
  - University of Pittsburgh at Bradford, 2002 (Box 151, Folder 27)